# André Picado

Lisbon, Portugal | picado.andre@gmail.com | +351 932 270 084 | www.linkedin.com/in/andre-picado/

#### **About Me**

Interested in software and product development, AI-driven decision making, and machine learning solutions. Master's degree in machine learning and data science with research in recommendation systems. A goal-oriented team player known for commitment, innovative thinking and open-minded collaboration.

## **Experience**

#### Software Engineer & Team Leader, Banetech

March 2024 – present

- Was involved in the **creation and development** of 3 **products**, a **live monitoring** application with integrated notifications, an **AI application** for service and infrastructure management and a customized **migration pricing calculator**.
- Became a Scrum Master and leader of a 5 person team responsible for the frontend development of all products. While in this role I
  welcomed and mentored 4 new developers.
- Managed communications with a client in the banking industry helping identify their needs and providing fast feedback and delivery.
- Lead stakeholder and product managers meetings to present product development status and discuss new features.

### **Software Engineer**, Banetech

October 2021 - March 2024

Banetech offers **services** and **products** related with high performance **integration platforms**.

• Full stack developer working on an existing product related with Enterprise Architecture, providing real time information using an Event Driven Architecture. The tech stack included Angular with TypeScript, Node, MySQL databases and git.

## **Education**

## Master of Science - Computer Science and Engineering

September 2020 - July 2022

Instituto Superior Técnico - Universidade de Lisboa

- Master's Degree with a specialization in Machine Learning and Data Science, having done a master's thesis that involved research
  and development of recommendation systems, content extraction from learning resources and student temporal profiling.
- Published thesis related articles on IEEE International Conference on Data Mining Workshops and INForum.

## **Bachelor of Science - Computer Science and Engineering**

September 2017 - July 2020

Instituto Superior Técnico - Universidade de Lisboa

• Bachelor's Degree with a special interest in linear algebra, calculus, data structures, algorithms, databases, software engineering, distributed systems.

## **Side Quests**

- Implemented and deployed a **language detection model** using Scikit-learn, and FastAPI. **Containerized** the application with Docker and **deployed** it on Heroku, transitioning from a Jupyter Notebook prototype to a scalable, production-ready solution.
- Developed a **photo uploading app** allowing authenticated users to upload photos, view their complete gallery, and inspect individual photos in detail. Using React and Next.js for the frontend. The app was **deployed** on Vercel and integrated with Clerk for user authentication and management, PostHog for analytics, and Sentry for error monitoring.
- Created a URL shortener service using Go, featuring concurrent processing for URL shortening and lookup with goroutines and channels to handle high-load scenarios. Integrated PostgreSQL for persistent data storage and Redis for caching, optimizing response times.

## Volunteering

#### **Banco Alimentar Contra a Fome**

• Assisted in gathering and organizing food items for Lisbon's largest food shelter

#### Corações Com Coroa

- Helped disassemble and package hospital equipment from a decommissioned Portuguese hospital that was then sent to Guiné-Bissau.
- Sold entries at the door of a charity concert event and helped explain the organization and purpose of the donations to guests.

### **Skills**

**Technologies:** Angular, Node, Git, TypeScript, Python, SQL, Go, PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, D3, React, Next, Docker, Scrum **Languages:** Portuguese (native), English (C2)

#### **Hobbies**